Empires fall. Love survives.
The Promise is a history, romance, drama film directed by Terry George.
Set during the last days of the Ottoman Empire, a love triangle develops between Mikael, a brilliant medical student,
the beautiful and sophisticated artist Ana, and Chris, a renowned American journalist based in Paris.
Mikael Boghosian, played by Oscar Isaac.
Ana Khesarian, played by Charlotte Le Bon.
Chris Myers, played by Christian Bale.
Reverend Dikran Antreassian, played by Daniel Giménez Cacho.
Garin, played by Tom Hollander.
Marta Boghosian, played by Shohreh Aghdashloo.
The Promise is a 2016 American epic historical war drama film directed by
Terry George, from a screenplay he co-wrote with Robin Swicord.
Set in the final years of the Ottoman Empire, the film stars
Oscar Isaac, Charlotte Le Bon and Christian Bale.
The plot is about a love triangle that develops between Mikael (Isaac), an Armenian medical student, Chris (Bale), an American
journalist, and Ana (Le Bon), an Armenian-born woman raised in France, immediately before and during the Armenian genocide.
The Promise premiered on September 11, 2016, at the Toronto International Film Festival and was released by Open Road
Films in the United States on April 21, 2017, on the 102nd anniversary of the week the genocide started.
The film received mixed reviews from critics and was a box office bomb, grossing just $12
million against its $90 million budget and losing Open Road over $100 million.
However, the studio noted the main purpose of the film was to bring attention to the story, not make money, with George saying that "audiences learn more from films today than they
do from history books." The film also features "The Promise", which was the final single released by Chris Cornell, who died less than a month after the film's U.S.
The film explores themes of journalist, love
triangle, world war i, artist, turkey.
The tone is emotional.